Guide to the Michael Letwin Papers TAM 464
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Michael Letwin Papers
1957-2010
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
TAM 464
39.5 Linear Feet (41 boxes)
Michael Letwin was involved with the International Socialists (IS) and later with the International Socialist Organization (ISO), founded by expelled members of the IS in 1977. For three decades Letwin was also active in the peace movement. Letwin was also president of the Association of Legal Aid Attorneys in New York City for 13 years until he lost re-election in 2002, in part because of his opposition to the war in Afghanistan. The first series (1 linear ft., processed), along with documentation of his own activities, the collection also contains a variety of materials regarding cooperative living at Morningside Gardens, in the Morningside Heights neighborhood of Manhattan. The second series (31.5 linear ft., unprocessed), contains subject files (1978-2007) on the Afghan and Iraq Wars; Criminal Justice, principally in New York City and New York State; Rudy Giuliani, Mayor of New York City, 1990-2001; Labor; New York City Police Department; Racism; Racist Violence.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions with the exception of Boxes 39-41; access to Boxes 39-41 is restricted until 2048.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Materials donated by Michael Letwin in circa 1977; additional materials were doanted in 1990, 2010, and 2018. The accession numbers associated with these gifts are 1977.004, 2010.042, and 2018.079.
Arrangement
Folders are arranged alphabetically in the first two series. Files for the third series have not been physically arranged by an archivist. These materials are in the order in which they were received by the donor.
Missing Title
Series I: Subject Files, 1957-1992.
Series II: Subject Files, 2010 Accession (Containing the subseries: Afghan and Iraq Wars; Criminal Justice; Giuliani, Rudy; Labor; New York City Police Department; Racism; Racist Violence)
Historical/Biographical Note
Michael Letwin was involved with the International Socialists (IS) at the time of a split between the majority of the party and a group known as the Left Faction. After the Left Faction split from the main body of the IS, the International Socialist Organization (ISO) was formed by Left Faction leaders Calvin and Barbara Winslow. In 1983 the ISO underwent a crisis when the leadership of the Winslows was called into question, and the Winslows stepped down from their leadership positions. Letwin was also president of the Association of Legal Aid Attorneys in New York City for 13 years until he lost re-election in 2002, in part because of his opposition to the war in Afghanistan.
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
International Socialists (U.S.) Records (TAM 088)
Scope and Content Note
The first series, Subject Files, 1957-1992, contains documentation of the International Socialists (IS) from July 1976 to March 1977, when a group of dissenters called the Left Faction was expelled. The collection has minutes of meetings from this time period, presentations given by members of the Left Faction, resolutions from both sides and correspondence between members of the IS, the International Socialists Great Britain (ISGB), the Socialist Workers Party (SWP) and the International Socialists Canada. The collection also contains information from Michael Letwin's grandmother, Manya Zurow, about the co-operative housing development Morningside Gardens. Included are meeting minutes from a variety of organizations managing the property, information about various services offered by Morningside Gardens, and items of ephemera from day-to-day living in the co-op. There are also files of Letwin's friend and collaborator Alina Tugend. The collection also contains a variety of flyers from peace movement activities from the 1960s through the early 1990s. The bulk of the material is from activities in New York City, but there is also information on activities in Los Angeles in the early 1970s. Most of the NYC material is from the Riverside Church Disarmament Program, but many organizations are represented in the collection. The second series, Subject Files, 2010 Accession (29 linear ft., unprocessed), contains subject files (1978-2007) on the Afghan and Iraq Wars, (6.5 linear ft.); Criminal Justice, principally in New York City and New York State (10 linear ft.); Rudy Giuliani, Mayor of New York City, 1990-2001 (2 linear ft.); Labor (1 linear ft.); New York City Police Department (10 linear ft.); Racism (6 linear ft.); Racist Violence (1 linear ft.). Each box in Series II is labeled with a list of contents (see box-level scope and contents below, in the container list). NOTE: This collection is housed offsite and advance notice is required for use.
The third series, Subject Files, 2018 Accession, consists of printed email correspondence, news articles and reports documenting Michael Letwin's research of and affiliation with the union organization Association of Legal Aid Attorneys, UAW Local 2325 (ALAA) and the non-profit organization Legal Aid Society (LAS) stationed in New York City. Memorandum, news releases, committee reports and email correspondence between Letwin and union members chronicle the activities of ALAA and LAS from the late 1960s to the late 2000s. Other emails document Letwin's campaign to become President of the ALAA in the late 1980s, his election in 1990 and his loss of re-election in 2002. Proposals, correspondence and literature illustrate Letwin's involvement with numerous projects during his presidency concerning public issues like racism, police abuse, discrimination in the workplace and affirmative action, the latter of which he was an active supporter of as a member of the Joint ALAA-Management Affirmative Action Committee. Correspondence from 2004 to 2008 concerns the LAS fiscal crisis which prompted hundreds of layoffs at the organization.
Legal aid |z New York (State) |z New York.; Iraq War, 2003-2011.; Afghan War, 2001-; Fliers (printed matter); Lawyers |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.; Minutes (administrative records); Racism |z New York (State) |z New York.; Socialists -- United States.; Correspondence.; Peace movements -- United States.; Lawyers -- Political activity -- New York (State) -- New York.; Morningside Heights (New York, N.Y.); Trotskyists |z United States.; Trotskyism |z United States.; New York (State); Housing, Cooperative.; Los Angeles (Calif.); Resolutions (administrative records); Giuliani, Rudolph W.; Association of Legal Aid Attorneys UAW Local 2325 (New York, N.Y.); Tugend, Alina; International Socialist Organization (U.S.); New York (N.Y.). Police Dept.; Riverside Church Disarmament Program (New York, N.Y.); International Socialists (U.S.); Letwin, Michael; Winslow, Calvin; Winslow, Barbara, 1945-
- Series I: Subject Files, 1957-1992., 1 Linear Feet (2 boxes)
  - 1974 National Campaign to Impeach Nixon (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - American Professors for Peace in the Middle East: Amos Kenan "A Letter to All Good People", 1968 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - American Veterans Movement (AVM), 1974 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Asssociation des Travailleurs Haitiens: Coalition for the Defense of Haitian Refugees, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Avoid Vietnam in Latin America (AVILA), undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Central America, undated, 1982, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Chile, undated, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Christic Institute, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Coalition against U.S. Intervention in Central America and the Caribbean, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Coalition to Stop the War in El Salvador, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Columbia University: Peace Movement, Local 1199, Radical Action Committee, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Committee in Solidarity with the People of El Salvador, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Demokratia: Students for a Free Greece, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Draper, Ann: "Women in Struggle", undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Dump Nixon Coalition, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Elections: New York City and National, undated, 1984, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Emergency Civil Liberties Committee, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Foreign Policy Council of New York Democrats, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Freedom Cafe, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - German American: "Rebirth of German Culture" (Program), undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Grant-Morningside Neighborhood News (Newsletter), 1959 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Grant Peace March (National and New York City), 1986 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Guatemala, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Impeach Richard Nixon: Peoples Action Union and April 27 Committee, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - International Socialist Organization (ISO): Internal Bulletins, Organizing Committee Minutes and Letters, Jun 1977-Sep 1983 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - International Socialists (IS): Documents, Correspondence, Jul 1976-Mar 1977 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - International Socialists (IS): Left Faction Statements, Correspondence, Presentations and Resolutions, Nov 1976-Mar 1977 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Inter-Religious Task Force on El Salvador and Central America, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Jewish Currents, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Joe Hill Collective: POWs: The Big Lie (Newspaper), undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - L.A. Committee for New Elections: Nixon Impeachment, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Letwin, Michael and Alina Tugend: Rejection Letters, Questionnaires and Flyer, 1983. 1992 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Letwin, Michael: "Blacks in the Military from Colonial Days to Integration", May 1984 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Letwin, Michael: "Blacks in the Military: From Vietnam to the Present", Jan 1985 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Los Angeles Anti-Imperialist Contingent: Nixon Impeachment, undated (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Los Angeles Student Coalition (LASC), 1990 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Lower East Side Mobilization for Peace Action (LEMPA), undated (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Mobilization Against the Draft (MAD), 1980 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Morningside Citizen's Coalition Newsletter, 1970-1973 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Morningside Co-op Super Market, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Morningside Gardens, undated, 1957-1988 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Morningside Gardens: Handbooks, Rules and Fees, 1953-1975 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Morningside Gardens Tenant Cooperators Committee (MGTCC): Minutes, 1958-1977 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Morningside Gardens: Trees, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Morningside Heights Housing Corporation: Board of Directors Minutes and Reports, 1958-1969 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Morningside Heights Housing Corporation: By-Laws, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Morningside Heights Housing Corporation: Elections, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Morningside Heights Housing Corporation: Interim and Annual Reports, 1963-1969 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Morningside Heights Housing Corporation: Security, undated, 1967-1982 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Morningside Heights Housing Corporation: Reports, 1959-1967 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Morningside Retirement and Health Services, 1966-1991 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Morningsiders for Reversing the Arms Race, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Morris Kominsky Book Committee, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - National Peace Action Council (NPAC), 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - New El Salvador Today (NEST), 1989 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - New York Mobilization for Justice and Peace in Central America and Southern Africa, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Next Middle East Crisis Coalition, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Nicaragua, undated, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Open the Gate Committee: Angela Davis Greeting Cards, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Pageant Players, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Palestine Solidarity Committee, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Peace Movement Flyers, undated, 1986, 1987, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Poetry Project: John Giorno Defense Fund, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Promoting Enduring Peace, undated, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Quakers: New York Yearly Meeting Newsletter, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Radio Actors' Workshop: Reverie Vance, "Know These Americans", undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Rank and File Committee for a Democratic Union within the NYCTA: Rank and File News (Publication), 1968 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Riverside Church, 1973-1990 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Riverside Church Disarmament Program, 1979-1992 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Students for a Democratic Society (SDS): Flyers and New Left Notes (Newspaper), undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Student Non-Violent Coordinating Committee (SNCC): Flyers, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Socialist Workers Campaign: Andrew Pulley, "How to Stop the Draft", 1980 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Songs and Poems, undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - South Africa: Apartheid, undated, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Soviet Jewry, undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Student Mobilization Committee: National Strike Bulletin (Newsletter), 1971 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Student Union for Peace and Justice, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Tugend, Alina: "Two Souths:The Impact of Involvement in Vietnam on the Civil Rights Movement, 1963-1968", Feb 1981 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - U.S. Anti-Imperialist League (USAIL): Beirut and Zionism, undated (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Veterans Fast for Life, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Vietnam Veterans, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Vietnam Veterans Art Group (VVAG), undated (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Woman's International League for Peace and Freedom, undated, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Series II: Subject Files, 2010 Accession, 1978-2007; 29 Linear Feet
  - Afghan and Iraq Wars, circa 2000s; 6.5 Linear Feet (7 boxes)
    - Afghan and Iraq Wars 1, 1988 - Oct 2006 (Box 3)
      General
      Contains: Democratic Party; London bombing (2005); Oil - International Trade; Colombia; Pakistan/Iran/Uzbekistan; Patriotism, US; Russia; SE Asia; Pro-War in US; Military Recruitment; Military Repression, US; Military Intervention (1979-), US; Panama; Central America, Contragate; Katrina (2005); Afghanistan
    - Afghan and Iraq Wars 2, 1999 - Jan 26, 2006 (Box 4)
      Contains: Gulf War 1991; Cuba, Left Criticism of; Imperialism, generally; Darfur; WMD, US Nukes; WMD, Iran; WMD, Korea; UN; Torture
    - Afghan and Iraq Wars 3, Oct 2, 2001 - May 27, 2007 (Box 5)
      Contains: New York City Labor Against The War; (NYCLAW) postings; NYCLAW digests.
    - Afghan and Iraq Wars 4, Sep 2001 - Apr 2006 (Box 6)
      Contains: 911 immediate impact - domestic; Bin Ladin evidence; 911 labor assistance to victims; 911 economic impact; 911 disaster victims; 911 Giuliani; 911 biological attack; Civil liberties.
    - Afghan and Iraq Wars 5, Feb 10, 2003 - Apr 16, 2007 (Box 7)
      Contains: Iraq, Iraq War
    - Afghan and Iraq Wars 6, c 1974 - Jun 6, 2006 (Box 8)
      Contains: Iraq; Undocumented Workers "Illegals."
    - Afghan and Iraq Wars 7, Dec 23, 2002 - Jun 3, 2006 (Box 9)
      Contains: Somalia; Korea; 911 HS; Korea; Iran
  - Criminal Justice, undated; 10 Linear Feet (10 boxes)
    - Criminal Justice 1, 1990 - 2001 (Box 10)
      Contains: AIDS; Bail; Black community position; Black crime; Broken Windows Theory; Children; Drugs: CIA involvement; Drugs: citizen patrols; Drugs: Civil liberties; Drugs: Colombia
    - Criminal Justice 2, 1988 - 2000 (Box 11)
      Contains: Offensive in NYC; Courts, Pro-prosecution; Drugs: courts; Drugs: crack, generally; Drugs: crack babies; Drugs: Crime lab; Crime rates; Dinkins crime plan; Giuliani crime plan
    - Criminal Justice 3, 1986 - Aug 21, 2001 (Box 12)
      Contains: District Attorneys, Prosecution; Death Penalty; Drugs: crime; Overview
    - Criminal Justice 4, 1989 - 2001 (Box 13)
      Contains: Drugs: drug courts; Drugs: education about; Drugs: National enforcement; Drugs: Entrapment; Drugs: Evictions, NYC; Drugs: Federal Policy 1988-; Drugs: Los Angeles; Drugs: Money Laundering; Drugs: legalization; Drugs: interdiction and use of the military
    - Criminal Justice 5, Mar 1982 - Mar 2001 (Box 14)
      Contains: Drugs: trade, turf, gangs (NYC); Drugs: treatment; Drugs: gangs (national); Drugs: genocide argument; Drugs: jail and prison (NY); Grand Jury; Judicial Appointments and conduct; Juries; Juveniles; Drugs: drug exception (national); Drugs: marijuana; Mental illness; Drugs: National Guard, use of; Drugs: needle exchange; Drugs: parole; Plea Bargaining; Prison-Industrial Complex; Drugs: Angela Thompson Sentence (NY); Central Park Jogger Case ("Wilding") 1989
    - Criminal Justice 6, 1979 - Nov 20, 1996 (Box 15)
      Contains: Racism: general overview and discussion; Racism: cocaine sentencing disparity; Racism: prosecutors; Racism: Judicial Commission on Minorities (1988); Racism: judiciary; Racism: prosecution of prominent blacks; Racism: reports; Racism: street level enforcement; Racism: sentencing
    - Criminal Justice 7, 1986 - 2000 (Box 16)
      Contains: Sentencing; Sentences; OJ Simpson Trial; Rodney King Trial
    - Criminal Justice 8, 2000 - Mar 6, 2007 (Box 17)
      Contains: Tobacco; Rockfeller Drug Laws, NYS; Misc. CJS to file
    - Criminal Justice 9, Oct 24, 1979 - 2000 (Box 18)
      Contains: California; Florida; LAPD; California; Rodney King
    - Criminal Justice 10, 1990 - Jan 24, 2002 (Box 19)
      Contains: By state; Phillip Pannell (v. Spath), 1990 NJ; Tyisha Miller Los Angeles Police Department, 1999
  - Giuliani, Rudy, undated; 2 Linear Feet (2 boxes)
    - Rudy Giuliani 1, 1994 - 2000 (Box 20)
      Contains: School chancellors; School uniforms; Secrecy; Sex; Suits against city; Strike contingency plans; Street signs; Taxis; Time Warner cable; Traffic and peds; Vendors; Welfare; Popularity; Press; As US Attorney; Animus; Aides; AIDS; Arts - Brooklyn Museum; Street artists; Bunkers; Car seizures; Charas; Character, ambition, personal; Racism, personal; Redbaiting; Protesters, gethering; City Hall gardens; NYC Charter reform
    - Rudy Giuliani 2, 1992 - Jan 15, 2002 (Box 21)
      Contains: City Council; City employee free speech; City Hall fortress; Contractors, vendors; Critics, misc.; CUNY; Defamation, character assassination; Dibrienza; DNA testing; Foreign government figures; Grammys; Opposition to; Haitians; Hanac; Donna Hanover; Health, personal; Homeless; Housing works; Judges; Law, Mafia; Manhattan Institute; Municipal unions; City Hall demo, riot; NYPD commissioner; Navy Yard; Public order; v. Pataki; Patronage, corruption; Pets; v. politicians
  - Labor
    - Labor, Oct 23, 1979 - May 2002 (Box 22)
      Contains: Labor notes 1979-2002; Songs, history, etc.; Labor movement; Inside strategy
  - New York City Police Department, undated; 10 Linear Feet
    - New York City Police Department 1, Oct 27, 1983 - 2002 (Box 23)
      Contains: To file; Brutality generally; Bystanders; Cadets; Civilian Complaint Review Board (CCRB)
    - New York City Police Department 2, 1972 - 2002 (Box 24)
      Contains: Community policing; Corruption, misc.; Equal Justice News; IAD/IAB corruption; Mollen Commission; Drugs corruption/abuse; Crime stats; Corrupt cops: drug rings tipping off mob; Black cops; Locurto; Internal racism; AIDS; Gay; Women; Desmond Robinson: black cop shot by white cop; Cop; Discrimination
    - New York City Police Department 3, 1989 - 2001 (Box 25)
      Contains: Drugs: DEA; Drugs: Drug Wars NYC; Drugs: Tactical Narcotics Teams (TNT), NYC; NYPD: DWI, by police; NYPD: evictions by; NYPD: evidence, handling of; NYPD: false arrests by; FBI: treatment of FDNY by; Gangs; NYPD: cuffing by; NYPD: treatment of Hassidim by; NYPD: treatment of homeless by; NYPD: hot pursuit and driving by; NYPD: lineups; NYPD: brutality lawsuits and awards; NYPD: media victims; NYPD: city budget; NYPD: commanders; NYPD: compensation; MOVE (Philadelphia); DEA; Drug enforcement by boro; Tactical Narcotics Teams (TNT)
    - New York City Police Department 4, 1985 - 2001 (Box 26)
      Contains: NYPD: general misconduct; NYPD: off-duty misconduct by officers; NYPD: Operation Condor; NYPD: policy and planning; NYPD: reform proposals; NYPD: spying; NYPD: 48-Hour Rule; NYPD: Giuliani v. Diallo Critics; NYPD: organizations v. abuse by; NYPD: Guiliani v. Patrick Dorismond; NYPD: overtime pay for; NYPD: Police Benevolent Association (PBA); NYPD: use of pepper spray by; NYPD: "Perp walk."
    - New York City Police Department 5, 1988 - 2002 (Box 27)
      Contains: Police in schools; NYPD: injury death; NYPD: cop v. cop; NYPD perjury; NYPD failed policy; Drug policy; Prosecution of; Protest - NYPD reaction; Puerto Rican Day parade
    - New York City Police Department 6, 1989 - 2002 (Box 28)
      Contains: NYPD: quality of life arrests; NYPD: arrest quotas; NYPD: racial profiling by; NYPD: radios, beatings with; NYPD: mistaken drug raids by; NYPD: rappers, treatment of; NYPD: recruitment by; NYPD: disclosure of discovery by; NYPD: residency requirement for officers; NYPD: cop v. cop retaliation; NYPD: unconstitutional search and seizure by; NYPD: street crime unit; NYPD: strikebreaking by; NYPD: strip searches by; NYPD: suicide by officers; Police: SWAT (national); NYPD: Brutality Task Force (1997); NYPD: training of; US Marshals; NYPD: ammunition; NYPD: choppers; NYPD: weapons used by; NYPD: street enforcement
    - New York City Police Department 7, 1992 - 2002 (Box 29)
      Contains: Beatings 1978-; Michael Stewart 9/15/1983; Anthony Patrick 2000; Ryan Zulia 2000; Lauren Sudeall 10/3/2000; Jason Rowley; Sheldon Gilbert 10/3/2000; Marie Claire Lim 10/3/2000; Errol Maitland 3/28/2000; Stacey Patton 4/2/2000; Thomas Washington (broom attack) 4/21/2000; Gilberto Reyes Jusino 3/1999; Donaldo Maloney 7/23/1999; Thomas Pizzato 1/13/1999; Alton Fitzgerald White 7/16/1999; Walter Avila 1998; Kenneth Banks 10/29/1998; Jean Charles 9/24/1998; Norman Batista 9/97; Kuken Kernisant 12/16/1997; Murrell 1997; Shane Daniels 9/1996; Harold Dusenbury 7/25/1996; Anthony Baez 12/24/1994; Ernest Sayon chokehold death 4/29/1994; Johnny Cronartie 1993; Edward Dominguez 1993; Yunas Mohammed 9/16/1992; William Smith death 1/29/1992; Michael Perez rape 1991; Federico Periera custody death 2/5/1991; Joanne Tunner 9/28/1990 video taped assault; Henry Hughes 1989; Juan Rodriguez restraint death 1/20/1988; Edwin Torres drowning death 4/19/1998; Larry Davis 1986; Cadets; Civilian Complaint Review Board (CCRB)
    - New York City Police Department 8, 1978 - 2002 (Box 30)
      Contains: NYPD: shootings 1973-1989; NYPD: Bernard Kerik; NYPD: Patrick Dorismond shooting (2000); NYPD: Abner Louima, assault on (1997); NYPD: Amidou Diallo shooting (1999)
    - New York City Police Department 9, 1988 - circa 2000 (Box 31)
      Contains: Precincts; Anti Bias unit; Crime lab; Correction; Housing Police Department; Medical examiner; NYS troopers; Transit police; Amadou Diallo
    - New York City Police Department 10, 1983 - 2001 (Box 32)